One Worthy as a Leader
(サジン)ハッ こんな問題
どんなにバカだろうと解けるだろ。
Any idiot can solve
a question like this.
《シラ : え!?》
ああ そうだ。
– Huh?
– Yeah, he's right.
(ネジ)では お前は
どの問題を解くというのだ？
So what question
are you going to solve?
教える筋合いはねえな。
Why should I tell you?
どの問題を解けばいいかが
わからなくて➡
Everyone is in a dilemma
because they don't know…
皆 悩んでいるはずだ。
which one to solve.
[モニタ](ネジ)他の仲間が
どれを選択するか➡
It's because they don't know
わからないからな。
which ones their teammates
will choose.
(シカマル)ネジが何かやる気だな。
Neji is planning something.
(テマリ)しかし
何か手を思いついたとして➡
But why would he tell the others
what he plans to do?
なぜ 他のやつに教えるんだ？
(シカマル)ネジの解き方では
そうする必要があるんだろう。
The method he plans
to use probably necessitates it.
(コムギ)お前は わかるのか？
Do you know?
仲間のことは 俺にもわからない。
I don't know about
my teammates either.
(シビレ)何だ それ。
What is that supposed to mean?
だが 俺が何点を取るか➡
But if there's a way to let them know
how many points I'll get,
仲間に伝えることができれば
問題は解決する。
I can solve the question.
ああ 伝えられればな。
That's if you can let them know.
振動で他の部屋に数を伝える。
I'll communicate the number
to the next room with vibration.
壁に ４発 振動を送る。
I'll send four vibrations
through the wall.
教室から出ることなく
壊すことなく伝える。
I'll relay the information without
leaving the room or destroying it.
(シビレ)だけど 壁を叩いて
合図したところで➡
But will just hitting the wall
get your message across?
それで
こちらの意図が伝わるのか？
４発の合図をどう考えます？
How would you interpret
four bangs on the wall?
(ヒナタ)もし 私に４回の合図が
聞こえてきたら…。
If I should hear four signals…?
(ヒナタ)私ともう１人に40点を取れと
言っているわけじゃない。
That wouldn't mean the other person
and I should score 40 points.
２人が40点ずつ取ったら80点。
If two takes 40 each,
that's 80 points.
これでは 合図をした人が 50点➡
Then if the one
who signaled takes 50,
40点 30点 ０点➡
40, 30, 0 points…
どれを解答しても➡
None of the combinations
totals 100.
100点になる組み合わせはない。
だから これは合図を出した人が➡
So it can be interpreted that the one
who signaled will take the 40-pointer.
40点を取るというメッセージだと
考えられる。
他の２人は 30点を取ればいい。
And the other two
can take the 30-pointers.
– I see.
– That makes sense.
源内とイナホもそう考えるかな…。
I wonder if Gennai and Inaho
will think the same way.
(シビレ)ミノジとタンゾウ 大丈夫か？
I hope Minoji and Tanzo
are okay.
各里で それぞれスリーマンセルを組み➡
Each village selected three genin
中忍試験に
乗り込んできた仲間だろう。
to make up their teams
for the Chunin Exams.
お互いの仲間を
信じてやることだな。
Everyone just has
to trust their teammates.
(コムギ)だけど なんでそれを
俺たちにも教えるんだ？
But why would you teach this
to all of us?
お前は 俺が いきなり
壁を４発叩いたら どう思う？
If I suddenly pounded
on the wall four times,
what would you think?
そりゃ 変に思う。
Well… Naturally, I'd get suspicious.
(ネジ)まあ 当然だな。
You would, right?
なら そう思う連中に
途中で妙な邪魔をされたくない。
And I didn't want you guys
to do something and interfere.
そこで あらかじめ
洗いざらい話したうえで➡
I figured I'd come clean
and let everyone in on this,
この くだらないペーパーテストを➡
and we can all pass
this stupid paper test.
参加者全員で
突破するのが目的だ。
(サジン/コムギ)全員!?
All of us?!
そうくるか。
全員合格とは➡
So that's his plan.
Everybody passes…
He really got you there, Mr. Proctor.
また 試験官泣かせだな。
ま あいつの統率力ってのが
よくわかったよ。
Well, I've gotten a good look
at his leadership skills.
《全員でだと？》
All of us?
なるほど あんたの言うとおりだ。
I see… You're right.
だが 他の教室に伝える役目は➡
But how about letting me pass on
the info to the other classes?
俺にやらせてもらえねえか？
かまわんが なぜだ？
Sure, but why?
木ノ葉ばかり
責任を負わせてもいられねえ。
I can't let the Hidden Leaf
do all the work.
教室を壊したら 俺が被る。
I'll take the blame if
the classroom is damaged.
振動で伝えればいいんだろ？
I just have to send vibrations, right?
ああ。
Yes.
はぁ～！
１！
One!
２ ３。
Two! Three!
４！
Four!
フッ。
おい ５回だぞ。
Hey, that was five!
(コムギ)どういうことだ？
What're you doing?
(サジン)全員で合格？
Everyone passes?
何 甘いこと言ってやがんだよ。
You've got to be kidding.
誰かが落ちなきゃ
試験の意味がねえだろ。
What's the sense of having a test
unless someone's eliminated?!
クッ こいつ。
W-Why you…!
– What a jerk!
– What's going on?
フハハハッ 今更 取り消せねえぜ。
It's too late now.
４回を送り直したら
混乱するだけだ。
If you send four vibrations again,
you'll only add
to the confusion.
別に５回なら５回でかまわない。
It doesn't matter
if it's five times.
何？
(ネジ)３回でもよかった。
What?
Three times is fine too.
メッセージを出せれば どれでもな。
As long as I get
the message out, any one will do.
どれでも？ ３回でも ４回でも➡
Any one? Three, four, or five…
They're all the same?
５回でも 同じだっていうのか？
ああ そうだ。 いや 少し違うな。
Yes. Well, it's slightly different.
(ネジ)俺が どの問題を解くかが
違ってくる。
The question I pick will change.
は？
あっ。
Huh?
(ミコシ)なるほど。
I see…
(サクラ)今のは 何かの合図。
That was a signal of some sort.
(キバ)やたら大声張り上げるよりは
確かに伝わるやり方だな。
It's definitely more efficient
than yelling something out.
(テンテン)でも なんで５回？
But why five times?
５回ってのは きっと
50点の問題じゃねえのか？
Five times must mean
the 50-point question.
それをどうするんだろう？
So what are we supposed to do?
そうか…。
I get it…
(サクラ)50点の問題を解いて
100点にするには➡
To get 100 points using
a 50-point question,
誰かが０点で 他の２人が
50点を解くパターンだけど➡
two members need
to solve the 50-pointer
and the third member
needs a zero.
メッセージを出した人が
50点を解くのはありえない。
Whoever signaled
won't solve the 50-pointer.
これはきっと そういう合図よ。
That's what the message
is telling us exactly that.
何だ？ それ。
What does that mean?
I'm saying the remaining two
would have to select
(サクラ)だから 他の２人が
50点と０点の➡
the 50-point or 0-point question,
どちらを解けばいいか
判断がつかないでしょ。
with no way of knowing
which to choose.
つまり 他の２人に 50点の問題を
解けと言ってるのよ。
So he's signaling both teammates
to both solve the 50-point question.
メッセージを出した人は
０点をとるってわけ？
So whoever signaled
will get zero points?
そういうことね。
受け取ったほうが➡
Exactly, hoping that each teammate
will think about the other
他の仲間のことも考えて
判断すると期待して。
and figure it out.
だけど 誰がメッセージ出したんだ？
So who sent the message?
誰かはわからないけど➡
I don't know,
このメッセージを出した教室の
みんなの意見が一致したのね。
but whoever sent it got everyone
in that classroom to agree.
でなきゃ こんな真似は無理よ。
Otherwise, it would've been impossible.
(シノ)つまり メッセージを出した
教室の受験生は➡
So, everyone in that classroom
that signaled will take zero points.
全員０点をとる。 なぜなら
これは 他の２人が➡
It's because this message
is signaling
50点ずつとれという
メッセージだからだ。
the remaining two members
to choose the 50-point question.
(リー)そういうことですか。
So that's what it means.
(源内)しかし
０点を選ぶなんて 大胆だぞ。
Still, opting to get zero points
is pretty gutsy.
３回の場合でも
こちらの意図は 伝わっただろう。
Even with three times,
my intention
would have been communicated.
その場合は
俺たちが 40点をとるとな。
In that case,
I'd take the 40-pointer.
どうしてわかる？
How can you tell?
30点 30点 40点で
100点の組み合わせにするなら➡
If the grouping is 30, 30,
and 40 for 100 points,
合図を出した人は
30点をとらない。
whoever sent the signal
won't take 30.
Because that'll leave
the remaining two
(ミコシ)合図を受けた２人の間で➡
どちらが40点をとるか
決められないからです。
to decide between 30 and 40 points,
and that won't work.
だから
合図を出した人が40点で➡
So whoever signals takes
the 40-pointer,
他の２人が30点をとればいい。
leaving the 30-pointer
to his two teammates.
てめえ だったらなんで
その説明をしなかった？
Damn you.
Why didn't you explain that earlier?
言ったはずだ
妙な邪魔をされたくないと。
I made it clear, didn't I?
That I didn't want any interference.
もし 他の仲間と意思疎通できる
術者がいれば➡
I was concerned that jutsu users
who can communicate silently
with their teammates
この全員合格というプランの
邪魔をすると思ったからな。
would foil my plan for everyone
to pass this round.
あなたは できるんですね？
You can, right?
フッ。
くっ…。
邪魔はさせない。
No one will get in my way.
ん…。
てめえこそ 邪魔すんじゃねえ！
Well, you're not getting in my way!
NO UNAUTHORIZED FIGHTING
試験官 戦闘を許可するか？
Proctor, are you going
to allow fighting?!
応答がなければ
許可するものとみなすが。
If you don't reply,
I'll assume you are.
ハハッ！ やる気かよ。
You want to fight?
許可してくれよ 試験官様！
(ネジ/サジン)ん？
Mr. Proctor, give us permission!
[スピーカ](シカマル)
一次は 筆記と言ったはずだ。
I made it clear that Round One
is a written exam.
[スピーカ]戦闘は禁止。
Fighting is prohibited!
[スピーカ]おとなしく 時間まで
問題を解くように。
Stop that racket and answer
the question before the time's up!
だそうだ。
チッ！
You heard him.
ネジのやつ 俺からヒントまで
引き出しやがった。
That Neji…
He even forced a hint out of me.
さっきの注意のことか？
In that warning you just issued?
教室に届いた５回の振動➡
Until now, there was a possibility
that the others would think
それを他の教室の連中が➡
試験官が出した音かもしれないと
疑う可能性もあったんだが➡
I was the one who
pounded five times.
試験官が
注意を出したということは➡
I warned them to keep quiet just now,
thus raising the possibility
他の教室の誰かがやった
可能性が高まったし➡
that it was someone in
a classroom who made those sounds.
事実 そうだからな。
And in truth, it was.
これで 全員100点か。
So every team will score 100 points?
いや そうとも限らないぜ。
No, not necessarily.
冷静に理論を重ねれば
ネジの結論に至るが➡
If they rationalize it calmly,
they'd agree with Neji…
どこまで冷静でいられるか➡
But just how calm can they remain?
どこまで仲間を信頼できるかは
また別の問題だ。
How much faith they have
in their teammates
is another problem all together.
What's the answer
that you prepared?
(テマリ)お前の用意した正解は何だ？
(シカマル)ん？ 俺？
You're asking me?
If you were one of
the test takers over there.
お前が受験者として
向こうにいたら。
俺だったら
影真似の術を応用する。
I'd use my Shadow Possession Jutsu…
But this question wouldn't exist
if I weren't the proctor.
だが
そもそも俺が試験官じゃなきゃ➡
この問題は存在しない。
だから 俺が解いたらという疑問も
存在しないだろう。
That's why there is no point
in me answering that question.
なんだ そのヘリクツは。
What are you quibbling about?
まっ どこまで仲間と
状況に対して➡
Anyway, it all boils down
to thinking carefully
about your teammates
and the situation.
考えを重ねるかだよ。
でも かなりの合格者が
出るだろうな。
Still, there's bound to
be many who pass.
二次試験が面倒そうだ。
And that'll make
the Second Round a pain.
(シカマル)砂隠れに迷惑はかけねえ。
I won't make trouble
for the Hidden Sand.
一次の問題は もう一つある。
There's another part to this exam.
[スピーカ](シカマル)制限時間だ。
Time's up.
[スピーカ]全員 答案用紙を
裏返しにしてくれ。
Everyone, flip your sheets over.
続いて 第２問。
Continuing to the second part
of the exam.
(みんな)えっ!?
[スピーカ]問題。
– What?!
– Huh?!
Question.
[スピーカ]チームで任務中 敵に見つかった。
Your team is on a mission
and the enemy spots you.
In order to shake off
their pursuit,
[スピーカ]追撃を振り切るため➡
one teammate must stay behind
as a decoy.
１人をオトリで残すとしたら
誰にするか。
Who will you choose…
[スピーカ]オトリは間違いなく
死ぬものとする。
knowing that the decoy
faces certain death?
えっ!?
Write down your answer on
that reverse side of your sheet.
[スピーカ]解答は 今 裏返した用紙を使え。
[スピーカ]３人とも答えが一致したチームを
合格とする。
In order to pass,
all three members on the team
must have the same answer.
And the member named as
the decoy will be considered killed
[スピーカ]オトリに選ばれ
名前を書かれた受験者だけは➡
and eliminated from the Exams.
死んだものとみなし失格とする。
えっ!?
[スピーカ]制限時間は３分だ。
You have three minutes for this.
始め。
Begin!
《いったい誰を…》
How does he expect us to choose…?
《砂文字》
Sand Letters…
《ムジン : ミジンにする… か》
So we'll go with Mijin?
《ミジン : なっ 俺!?》
Me?!
《クソッ》
Damn it…
MIJIN
《昔の第七班なら 答えはナルトね。
In our old Team 7,
it would have been Naruto.
だって あいつが自分で
きっと そう書くから》
Because he would probably
write his own name down.
((ナルト : サクラちゃん サスケ➡
Sakura! Sasuke!
(俺がオトリになるから
２人は逃げろってばよ))
I'll be the decoy,
so you two make a run for it.
《サクラ : だから答えは…》
So my answer is…
NARUTO
NARUTO           NARUTO
ME
((サスケ : このウスラトンカチが！
You idiot!
うっせえ！
だいたい２人揃って➡
Shut up!
And thanks a lot, you two,
for naming me the decoy?!
オトリは俺って 何なんだよ！
NARUTO
What about you writing down "Me"?
お前こそ 「オレ」って何だよ！
お前が自分で
自分を選ぶだろうからって➡
NARUTO
We figured you'd choose yourself,
so Sakura and I wrote "Naruto."
俺も サクラも
ナルトにしたんだろうが！
お前が
「オレ」と書くなんて読めるか！
ME              NARUTO
Like we were supposed
to know you'd write "Me"!
ひっでえよ ２人とも！
You're mean, both of you!
(仲間を大切にしないやつは
クズだ～！))
Shinobi who don't value
their comrades are scum!
《答えはナルトじゃない。
The answer isn't Naruto.
今の私の仲間は いのとチョウジ。
だから…》
My teammates now
are Ino and Choji…
So…
《いの : サクラ！ どうしよう。
Sakura!
What'll we do?
I can't choose either of you!
誰かを選ぶなんてできない。
シカマルったら何考えてんだろう》
What is Shikamaru thinking?
《いの チョウジにも伝えて。
答えは…》
Ino, please relay this to Choji too.
The answer is…
《えっ そんな》
Huh?! But that's…!
(イズモ)答案用紙を回収する。
I'll be collecting your papers.
採点が済むまで教室で待機。
Wait in your classrooms
until the papers are graded.
合格者は アナウンスで
校庭に呼び出すことになっている。
Those who passed will be
called out to the schoolyard.
(綱手)そちらから来るとは
珍しいな。
You rarely visit.
To what do I owe this pleasure?
(コハル)少し 耳に
入れておきたいことがあってな。
There's something you need to know.
(綱手)二次試験の試験官に
木ノ葉の者はいらぬというのか？
You don't need Hidden Leaf proctors
for the Second Round?
(カンクロウ)砂隠れで すべてを➡
The Hidden Sand would like
to handle everything ourselves.
取り仕切らせて
いただきたいのです。
(綱手)理由は？
And the reason for that?
The site of the Second Round
is known as the Demon Desert.
二次試験会場の魔の砂漠は➡
It's extremely dangerous even for
those of us familiar with the terrain.
土地勘のある我々でも
危険な場所です。
警備上の都合と ご理解願えると。
For the sake of security,
we ask for your understanding.
その警備とやらは誰のためだ？
For whose security, may I ask?
Naturally, for the participants.
もちろん受験者のためです。
受験者の担当上忍は
砂隠れの里に同行する。
The jonin in charge of the entrants
will accompany them
to Hidden Sand Village.
それは譲らぬぞ。
(カンクロウ)はい それでかまいません。
That is not open to negotiation.
Yes, that's fine.
どう思う？
(ホムラ)きな臭いな。
What do you think?
Sounds suspicious.
ああ 何かを隠している。
Yes, they are hiding something.
だが臭うのは砂ばかりではない。
But the Sand are not the only ones.
雨隠れの反応はどうなのじゃ？
How have the Hidden Rain responded?
我々も先ほどダンゾウに呼ばれての。
Danzo asked to see us earlier.
あっ。
Even though he's confined
under house arrest,
謹慎中の身だが あやつも
それなりの人脈を持っておる。
he still has his connections.
((ダンゾウ : わしが 雨隠れの長
山椒魚の半蔵に➡
You are aware that I helped
Hanzo of the Salamander,
the leader of the Hidden Rain?
手を貸していたことは
知っておるな？
うむ。
おぬしが根を束ねておった頃よな。
That was when you were
in charge of the Foundation.
わしが失脚したあとも➡
I continued to communicate with him
secretly even after I was ousted.
半蔵とは
密かに連絡は取り合っていた。
ダンゾウ おぬしまさか？
Danzo, you didn't…?
(ダンゾウ)その半蔵からの連絡が
ふいに途絶えた。
But Hanzo abruptly
stopped contacting me.
わしを見限ったというのなら➡
If he stopped trusting me,
さまざまな秘密を知るわしを
おびき出し➡
he would've lured me out
and killed me
since I know so many secrets.
殺せばいいものを そうもせぬ。
But he didn't.
Something has happened to Hanzo.
半蔵に何かあったのであろう。
何かとは？
Like what?
わしは雨隠れで 何か
事件があったと にらんでいる。
I believe there's been
an incident in Hidden Rain Village.
最悪 半蔵はもうこの世にいない。
まさか。
In the worst case,
he's no longer in this world…
How can that be?
On the outside, Hanzo is still
the leader of the Hidden Rain.
表向き
雨隠れの長は 半蔵のままぞ。
この状況下で参加してきた
雨隠れの受験者には➡
Please warn Princess Tsunade
to be extremely wary of the entrants
sent by the Hidden Rain.
(くれぐれも注意するようにと
綱手姫に伝えてくれ))
確かに伝えたぞ。
Well, you have been warned.
(綱手)あのダンゾウが そんなことを。
Danzo of all people asked you this?
(コハル)鷹派だとか忍の闇とか
呼ばれる男だが➡
He may be called a hardliner
and the darkness within shinobi…
But there is no doubt
木ノ葉のためを思って
動いていることには違いない。
that he operates all for
the sake of the Hidden Leaf.
雨隠れか。
The Hidden Rain, eh…
監視を強化しなければな。
We must increase surveillance.
砂の件もある。
There's also the Sand to think of.
受験者の担当上忍には
この件を伝えておこう。
I will inform the jonin in charge
of the entrants about this.
Just the jonin of the teams
who pass the first round?
(コハル)一次試験を通過した
チームのだけでよいな。
ああ。
Yes.
クソ。
Damn it…
あ～。
Well…
Those of you here have passed
the First Round. Congratulations.
ここにいるのが
一次試験の合格者だ。
(シカマル)おめでとう。
ネジがあの合図を
送ってくれたんですね。
Neji, you sent that signal, right?
Thanks to you, we made it.
おかげで助かったわ。
正確には 砂のそいつが
やってくれたんだがな。
Truth be told,
that guy from the Sand did it.
お前ら なんで３人いるんだ？
How come all three of you made it?
Didn't the decoy get disqualified?
オトリとして選ばれた１人は
失格じゃねえのかよ。
３人の答えが
一致すれば合格だ。
The rule said all three had
to have the same answer.
俺たちは 誰も選ばなかった。
We didn't choose anyone.
(サジン)何!?
白紙で出しましたから。
What?!
We all turned in a blank sheet.
白紙!? ３人とも!?
Blank? All three of you?!
(テンテン)
仲間を１人だけ犠牲になんて➡
There's no way we'd sacrifice
a comrade.
できるわけないでしょ？
(２人)くっ。
Take a look…
見ろ ３人とも生き残ったチームが
どれだけあるのか。
at how many teams passed
with all three members.
(ユカタ)ごめんね 問題の意味
全然わからなくて。
I'm sorry I couldn't figure out
the question.
It's okay!
(マツリ)大丈夫。
(ミコシ)そう思って➡
We coordinated things
with that in mind.
僕たちで調整したのですから。
I know!
うん ２人を信じて
何も書かなかったの。
I trusted you two and
didn't write anything.
書けなかったでしょ？
(ミコシ)あぁ。
More like couldn't, right?
You guys!
お前ら～。
一次突破だ～。
We passed Round One!
You can transfer thoughts,
but that backfired on you, eh.
(ネジ)意思疎通のできる
お前たちの能力が仇になったな。
いや 他の仲間を
見殺しにすると考えた時点で➡
Well…
Thinking about letting a teammate die
was already the wrong answer.
それは 正解ではなかったんだ。
てめえ。
Why you…
二次試験を担当する
砂隠れのテマリだ。
I'm Temari of the Sand.
I'm in charge of Round Two
of the Exams.
Too many teams passed
the first round,
一次の合格者が多いので➡
so we're going to narrow it down
some more.
更に この中から
足切りをさせてもらう。
何だよ 足切りって。
Hey, what do you mean
"narrow it down"?!
First off, Round Two is also
a team battle.
(テマリ)まず 二次試験もチーム戦だ。
３名揃っていないチームは➡
Any team without its third member
will be disqualified!
この場で不合格だ。
何だって？
What?!
そのうえで二次試験は
砂隠れの里で行う。
Furthermore, Round Two will be held
in the Village of the Hidden Sand.
魔の砂漠監視所が集合場所だ。
We will meet at
the Demon Desert checkpoint.
Although there is a clear route
(テマリ)木ノ葉と砂の間のルートは
確立されているとはいえ➡
between the Hidden Leaf
and Hidden Sand Villages,
どんなに急いでも
忍の足で３日はかかる距離だ。
it will take a shinobi three days,
no matter how fast he or she may be.
A messenger hawk has been sent to
the Hidden Sand with these instructions.
あの伝書鷹で
砂隠れに連絡を送った。
到着順の下位30名は
その場で失格にしろとな。
"After the first 30 arrive,
all who follow are to be disqualified."
(テマリ)なお 一次同様
道中は戦闘禁止だ。
Finally, as in Round One,
fighting is prohibited en route.
バトルは二次で
思う存分やらせてやる 以上！
You can fight to your heart's content
in Round Two.
That is all.
リー テンテン。
(２人)あっ。
Lee, Tenten…
He's quick to assess a situation,
after all.
やっぱ あいつ
状況判断が早いわ。
What's wrong?
You're dismissed!
どうした？
以上と言ったはずだぞ。
Ino, Choji!
いの チョウジ。
何だ？
あ～ わかった！
Oh, I get it!
足切りの競争は
もう始まっているんだ！
The elimination race has
already begun!
用意 ドンくらい言ったらどうだ？
Couldn't you at least
have said, "ready, set, go"?
これは中忍試験だ アカデミーじゃない。
This is the Chunin Exams.
Not the Academy.
あれ？
(マツリ)ちょっとユカタ。
Huh?
– Hey, Yukata!
– Get moving!
急ぎたまえ。
Maybe next time, we should stick
to an ordinary scholastic test.
次回はもっと普通に学力を問うか。
一番で到着しましょう。
Let's get there first!
There's no advantage
to being the first to arrive.
一番になっても
特にいいことないわよ。
あっ。
白眼。
Byakugan!
There's one team ahead of us.
俺たちの前に ひと組いる。
(２人)えっ？
風影様 中忍選抜試験
第一次試験が終了しました。
Lord Kazekage…
Round One of
the Chunin Exams is over.
受験者たちは 現在
砂隠れに向かっています。
The participants are now heading
towards the Hidden Sand Village.
(我愛羅)そうか。
I see.
二次試験に備えろ。
Get ready for Round Two.
The people targeting you
are stepping up their efforts.
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
If you casually go out there,
you'll be playing into their hands!
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！ にっぽんの歌』。
オープニングを飾るのは
昭和の名曲 『あゝ上野駅』です。